bloomsmag.com 2018-06-29

# Privacy Policy – Blooms Mag

At Bloomsmag, we respect your privacy, and we understand the importance of the information you entrust to us. This Privacy Policy describes our practices concerning the information collected by Bloomsmag, LLC (“Bloomsmag”, “we”, “us”, “our”) through the use of (i) our Bloomsmag, website (the “Website”) and (ii) our Bloomsmag mobile applications (collectively, the “Services”).

Below we describe what information we collect when you use our Services, how we protect that information, how long we retain it, with whom we share it, and what your privacy options are. By using the Services, you consent to our collection and use of your information as described in this Privacy Policy. The Privacy Policy is incorporated by reference into and is made a part of the Terms of Service.

We will continue to evaluate this Privacy Policy against new technologies, business practices, and our users’ needs, and may make changes to the Privacy Policy accordingly. Please check this page periodically for updates. If we make any material changes to this Privacy Policy, we will post the updated Privacy Policy here, along with its effective date, and for material changes will notify you by email or by means of a notice on our Website. Your continued use of the Services after our posting of changes to this Privacy Policy means that you agree to be bound by such changes.

**1\. What information do we collect about you?**

We explain below the main ways that we collect and process information about you.  
Information You Provide To Us:

Your use of the Services may require registration, in which case we will ask you to provide certain personal information, including an email address, username, and password. If you are enrolling in any of our Webinars and/or Courses, your registration may require further information, including, without limitation, address and/or phone number. You may also decide to provide us with some optional personal/demographic information to enhance your profile, such as your full name, professional title, year of birth, company name, and household income, investment interests, retirement information, and communications preferences. If you are a Financial Advisor participating in our Advisor Insights program, you may provide us further information about your credentials, including, without limitation, your broker CRD number, job title, state, zip code, phone number, professional website URL, biographical information and profile picture.

**You may also provide personal information to us, if you choose to:**

submit a help request, a customer services inquiry or other inquiry to us, or fill in any other forms for the purposes of receiving our Services;  
participate in some of the features accessible via the Services (for example, message boards, games, surveys, polls, promotions, contests, or sweepstakes);  
sign up to receive any information and/or services from any third party provider or partner using our Website (If you submit information to a third party provider or partner, please note that their use and disclosure of your information is subject to their own privacy policy);  
contact us about employment opportunities posted to the Services; or  
otherwise use the Services in a manner that you have requested.

Depending on which of these or any other Services you use, the personal information you provide may include your name, email address, user name, home address, telephone number, and information posted by you on sites accessed via the Services. Please be aware, that by posting information to message boards, chat groups or social networking facilities available via the Services, you will be making this information available to other users of these Services to the public. You should be careful about revealing any sensitive details about yourself.  
If you purchase Courses through the Bloomsmag Academy, please note that we do not currently collect or retain credit card numbers internally. We partner with third party payment providers. All direct payment gateways are required to adhere to the standards set by PCI-DSS as managed by the PCI Security Standards Council, which is a joint effort of brands like Visa, MasterCard, American Express and Discover. PCI-DSS requirements are intended to promote the secure handling of credit card information.  
Email Referral:

We also have features that allow you to send an email to yourself and/or others about an item on our site. If you choose to use our email referral service, you will be required to provide the e-mail address or addresses that will be used in the notification. Upon form submission an email will be generated to your recipient(s) inviting them to visit the URL you have recommended. We do not store this information other than for the sole purpose of sending this one-time e-mail.

Information Collected Automatically:  
When you use the Services, we automatically collect and store certain information about your computer or device and your activities, including:

  1.     1. IP address of your computer
    2. Unique device identifiers
    3. Technical information about your computer or mobile device such as type of device, mobile device ID number, web browser (Internet Explorer 8, etc.), other browser information (e.g. size, connection speed and connection type), and operating system or platform (Mac, Windows XP, etc.)
    4. Your preferences and settings (time zone, language, etc.)
    5. Internet provider or mobile carrier name  
The URL of the last webpage you visited before visiting the Website
    6. Information about your activity on the Services (e.g., your search queries, mis-formatted DNS entries, search results selected, clicks, pages viewed, search history, comments)
    7. If you are using a mobile device, your mobile device’s geographic location (specific geographic location if you’ve enabled collection of that information, or general geographic location automatically). Please see the section “Mobile Device Location Information” below for further information.

Cookies and Similar Technologies:

We, as well as other companies, use tracking technologies to collect and store data about your computer or mobile device and your activities on the Services. When you visit our sites, we place cookies, pixel tags, web beacons and other such similar technologies to collect and store the information we automatically collect about your computer, device and Services usage. A cookie is a small text file that is stored on your computer and a pixel tag (also called a web beacon or clear GIF) is a tiny graphic with a unique identifier, embedded invisibly on a webpage (or an online ad or email). We use the term “cookies” in this policy to refer to cookies and all such similar technologies. We use these technologies to store your preferences and track your use of the Services. Ad companies place cookies on your computer to track your activities across various sites so that they can display targeted ads. Some ad companies and game developers use “flash cookies” for ads and games that use Flash media technology.

There are two broad categories of cookies: (1) first party cookies, served directly by us to your computer or mobile device, and (2) third party cookies, which are served by a third party on our behalf. Cookies have a lot of jobs. For example, our cookies enable us to recognize you (e.g. as a registered user) when you visit our website and to store your preferences and settings. We use third party cookies for functionality, performance / analytics, advertising and social media purposes. Cookies from advertising companies, for example, help to ensure that the advertisements you see online are more relevant to you and your interests. To understand more about cookies and pixel tags, click here.

**How To Control Or Delete Cookies** :

Most browsers allow you to change your cookie settings. Users can usually set their browsers to block all third-party cookies (which are those set by third-party companies collecting information on websites operated by other companies), block all cookies (including first-party cookies such as the ones Bloomsmag uses to collect search activity information about its users), or block specific cookies. These settings will typically be found in the “options” or “preferences” menu of your browser. In order to understand these settings, the following links may be helpful, otherwise you should use the “Help” option in your browser for more details.
